<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://blog.roti.express//en/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://blog.roti.express//en/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2019-02-12T09:52:41+01:00</updated><id>https://blog.roti.express//en/</id><title type="html">Roti.express Blog</title><subtitle>Le Blog Agile de Roti.express</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Perfection Game</title><link href="https://blog.roti.express//en/perfection-game-en" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Perfection Game" /><published>2019-02-01T09:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-02-01T09:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://blog.roti.express//en/perfection-game-en</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.roti.express//en/perfection-game-en">&lt;p&gt;“Perfection game” or the art of “Doing better tomorrow”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Feedback is good. Continuous improvement is better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the conclusion we came to.
We brainstormed with Louis VAREILLE, our partner at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reuniologie.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;International School of Meetingology.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result of this joint initiative is the introduction in our application of a new feature called “Perfection Game”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us explain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;doing-better-tomorrow&quot;&gt;Doing better tomorrow?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is quite simple but very effective, it is about questioning the participants on: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The two priorities they think they need to work collectively on, so as to do better next time?””&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to guide the choices of the participants we have, with the help of Louis, selected the 10 most recurring paths of progress.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/perfectiongame1_en.png&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After processing the answers of the participants the system proposes the two most supported priorities..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the facilitator just has to validate these priorities and get the team working to treat them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;engage-the-teams-in-a-process-of-change&quot;&gt;Engage the teams in a process of change?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/perfectiongame2_en.png&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Why two priorities and no more?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;« Who graps all, looses. » The poet would say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;« Rome was not done in a day » the historian would say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;« One step after another » the wise man would say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To avoid getting lost, do not fight all fights at the same time! Remember, it is a process of continuous improvement. The goal is not to trigger a big bang but to climb the stairs of progress, one step at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as Louis reminds us in his book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.fr/Vivre-vie-Mode-Skype-simples/dp/154973895X/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1549358652&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=louis+vareille&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“Le bohneur au travail”&lt;/a&gt; ; the observation of progress is one of the greatest sources of joy in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;you-are-an-administrator-of-rotiexpress--how-to-proceed&quot;&gt;You are an administrator of roti.express … how to proceed?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/perfectiongame3_en.png&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; /&gt;
1- When creating the poll, activate the “Perfection Game”&lt;br /&gt;
2- Participants will be invited to answer during the ROTI survey &lt;br /&gt;
3- Then the TOP-2 priorities appear on your administration page.&lt;br /&gt;
4- Participants will find them later in the debriefing session&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;« Once you start measuring, you start improving. »&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Antoine Durand</name></author><category term="Features" /><summary type="html">“Perfection game” or the art of “Doing better tomorrow”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Carousel of comments</title><link href="https://blog.roti.express//en/carousel-en" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Carousel of comments" /><published>2018-12-12T09:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-12-12T09:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://blog.roti.express//en/carousel-en</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.roti.express//en/carousel-en">&lt;p&gt;It is not Christmas yet and we are already offering you a present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something simple, which we have often been asked, something obvious right in front of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The carousel of favorite comments to embed in your site..&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is this gift? I can hear you already telling me: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I do not need wooden horses for my site”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You got it I’m sure, there’s no connection! 😂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are talking here about the comments you have collected during your &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.roti.express/digital-roti&quot;&gt;ROTI surveys&lt;/a&gt; and that you want to highlight on your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we imagined a carousel in which the “selected pieces” scroll harmoniously on your site. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend was already doing it with snapshots and we talked about it again at the HappyTech Summit; It was high time we industrialized the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Team administrators can click on the icon ❤️ just below their favorite comments. They are then sent to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://roti.express/favorites&quot;&gt;special page&lt;/a&gt; that allows you to make some changes to preserve anonymity and correct any spelling errors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All you have to do is copy the four lines of HTML code and paste them into your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Il ne reste plus qu’à copier les quatre lignes de code &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/code&gt; pour les coller dans votre site.
&lt;strong&gt;There you go.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://roti.express/carousel/7nGE2vzmB787gXwzd?lang=en&quot; style=&quot;border:0;width:100%;height:250px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, the carousel automatically adapts to cell phone view if your site manages it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:survey@roti.express&quot;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt; if you have troube integrating the carousel in your site, I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; I wish you happy Christmas holidays 🎄, succulent Rotis 🍖  and many carousel rides 🎠.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Guillaume Darbonne</name></author><category term="Features" /><summary type="html">It is not Christmas yet and we are already offering you a present.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">12 symptoms of Meeting-Mania</title><link href="https://blog.roti.express//en/12_symptoms_meeting-mania" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="12 symptoms of Meeting-Mania" /><published>2018-11-18T09:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-11-18T09:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://blog.roti.express//en/12_symptoms_meeting-mania</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.roti.express//en/12_symptoms_meeting-mania">&lt;p&gt;Meeting-Mania within the company may occur in many forms. In this article you will find the 12 most common symptoms, if you recognize one or more of them you may as well be affected!
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/meetingmania.png&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;25%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-the-number-of-meetings-increases&quot;&gt;1/ The number of meetings increases&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of meetings per day and week is increasing over time, at first it was exhilarating but for some time it has been out of control, I cannot cope anymore …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I was invited to this meeting, I do not know why, but they consult me! Does it mean that my opinion is important?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-meetings-are-getting-longer&quot;&gt;2/ Meetings are getting longer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last Thursday we were efficient, after 20 minutes everything had been decided, but the host kept on talking and we drifted on other topics and had a cup of coffee together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I enjoyed spending time with my colleagues, but couldn’t we let people go once important decisions have been made?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-finding-a-meeting-room-has-become-a-struggle&quot;&gt;3/ Finding a meeting room has become a struggle&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting rooms are always occupied and you have to book them a week in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We are currently testing an application to optimize the booking since it’s become so complicated, but is this really the core of the matter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-the-diaries-are-only-meetings&quot;&gt;4/ The diaries are only meetings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our diaries are full of meetings from Monday 8am to Friday 6pm, you now need to set up a 3 people meeting 15 days in advance to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We are never at our desks because we spend most of our time meeting. When will we get the real work done?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-participants-do-something-else-during-the-meeting&quot;&gt;5/ Participants do something else during the meeting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I have meetings all the time I have to find some time to handle the daily work and answer my e-mails. So I always take my laptop and my phone to be multi-task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The other day a colleague was eating his sandwich during the meeting, he validated everything we said but did he really listen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-we-reassure-ourselves-with-a-lot-of-meetings&quot;&gt;6/ We “reassure ourselves” with a lot of meetings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other day I participated in a meeting that lasted 1 hour and we collectively decided on a totally unimportant matter .. I understood after that it was better to decide all together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The organizer prefered gathering 7 people to get an “amen” instead of deciding alone .. Did this meeting take place at the expense of deep thinking?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;7-the-agenda-is-non-existent&quot;&gt;7/ The agenda is non-existent&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the meeting is not prepared at all and we simply meet to talk about a topic. The talks are certainly very interesting but we do not understand where we are going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The notion of purpose or agenda is totally absent. Why not explain before to people the reason they are gathered?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;8-we-start-and-finish-systematically-late&quot;&gt;8/ We start and finish systematically late&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The guests have a lot of trouble being on time, they always have good reasons: “we were looking for the room, we got caught in something else …” and then there are so many topics to deal with that we rarely get everything done!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Respecting the time of others is the first of the courtesies! Why not impose punctuality and designate a “timekeeper”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;9-no-post-meeting-action-plan&quot;&gt;9/ No post-meeting action plan&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided a lot of things which represents a great step forward but it’s not really clear on “Who should do what and when?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s obvious that at the next meeting nothing will have progressed .. Why don’t we make a todo-list?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;10-some-people-do-not-open-their-mouths&quot;&gt;10/ Some people do not open their mouths&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We sometimes see people in meetings who do not say a word, they were invited “for info” to listen to what is said and to be kept informed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The casting is obviously wrong, why inflict that upon them? Why not just send them the report?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;11-speaking-time-is-monopolized&quot;&gt;11/ Speaking time is monopolized&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday meeting with the manager is always the same ; on the scheduled time he talks for 50 minutes of soporific figures and we must fight to say a word for the remaining 10 minutes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What if we tried letting everyone present speak, just to see. Why not organize a distribution of speaking time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;12-its-difficult-to-suggest-any-improvement&quot;&gt;12/ It’s difficult to suggest any improvement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We often have lots of good ideas for doing better next time, but it’s hard to get things moving in a context where meeting has become a lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You probably are not the only one thinking that, and you probably have the solution. Why not organize an evaluation of the meeting to collect feedback, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://roti.express&quot;&gt;ROTI&lt;/a&gt; for example?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(à suivre !)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Antoine Durand</name></author><category term="Meeting-mania" /><summary type="html">Meeting-Mania within the company may occur in many forms. In this article you will find the 12 most common symptoms, if you recognize one or more of them you may as well be affected! 1/ The number of meetings increases The number of meetings per day and week is increasing over time, at first it was exhilarating but for some time it has been out of control, I cannot cope anymore … I was invited to this meeting, I do not know why, but they consult me! Does it mean that my opinion is important?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Guide: getting massive feedback for events</title><link href="https://blog.roti.express//en/events-en" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guide:  getting massive feedback for events" /><published>2018-10-16T18:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-10-16T18:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://blog.roti.express//en/events-en</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.roti.express//en/events-en">&lt;p&gt;You are an organizer of Conferences, REX, TEDx or other events of this type? You probably know better than us that getting feedback is a real puzzle that can be very time consuming and very expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;automating-the-taking-of-feedback&quot;&gt;Automating the taking of Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://roti.express&quot;&gt;Roti.express&lt;/a&gt; platform  allows to make massive feedback in a simple, fun, and really effective way! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With us, the steps for capturing feedback, recording answers and providing results are fully automated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And icing on the cake ; everything happens in real time! You’ll be able to observe the arrival of the results and the analytics filling as your event unfolds. All you need is a smartphone, a tablet or a computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of what we did for &lt;a href=&quot;https://roti.express/feedback/aes2018&quot;&gt;Agile en Seine 2018&lt;/a&gt; (500 participants)
&lt;a href=&quot;https://roti.express/feedback/aes2018&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aes_background1.png&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;60%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
That’s rather impressive, isn’t it? Let’sexplain how it works ;follow the guide!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-1-ask-for-a-quotation&quot;&gt;Step 1: Ask for a quotation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An event of this magnitude is more complicated than a meeting and we’ll need to have some information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of participants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date and Duration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of sessions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you need us on the site?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Why are we asking all this?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
In order to ensure the quality of the incoming feedback and to receive important loads on the platform we provision machines (servers, load balancer etc ..) to absorb the peaks of simultaneous connections.
&lt;br /&gt;All this is planned up ahead, and requires a little work on our part!
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/event_offering_en.png&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;30%&quot; /&gt;
The quote request is done through e-mail, you can contact us directly at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:survey@roti.express&quot;&gt;survey@roti.express&lt;/a&gt;. We’ll get back to you as soon as possible!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-2-your-workspace&quot;&gt;Step 2: Your workspace&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we have reached an agrement we will create your workspace, then you will receive a link to join the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is from this space that you will be able to administer the event: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choose a name and customize your logo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create and set polls&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Retrieve QR-Codes and share links&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;View all detailed results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your workspace is open for a period of 30 days: the opening takes place 15 days before the event to prepare it and the closing is 15 days later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data you have collected does not disappear from the platform, and the sharing pages remain accessible (unless you specify otherwise). When we say “closing” the platform we mean that the participants can not vote after a period of 15 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-3-creating-polls&quot;&gt;Step 3: Creating polls&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are then getting into the heart of the subject, we must create for each intervention the associated survey by indicating:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The name of the session&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The name of the speaker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date, time and duration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;as well as some parameters (visibility, anonymous answers, etc.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be clear if your event consists of 30 sessions, it will be necessary to create 30 polls! This is a bit of work, we recommend doing it a few days in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-4-qr-codes-and-sharing-links&quot;&gt;Step 4: QR-Codes and sharing links&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the polls have been created you will get two things&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The share link (URL to reply to the survey)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A QR-Code, which also points to this sharing link &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These elements will allow you to collect feedback automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;QR codes&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The best way to get feedback is “while they’re still hot” just at the end of the intervention. You will need to ask your speakers to be kind enough to integrate a QR-Code on the last slide of their PowerPoint presentation.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/hand.png&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Affiches&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
From your workspace you have the possibility to create posters that contain the name of the session and the QR-Code, we recommend placing these posters at the exits of the conference rooms and printing them in A3 format.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aes_wall.png&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-5-the-d-day&quot;&gt;Step 5: The D day&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Explain carefully the approach to the speakers&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
From what we have been able to observe the number of answers obtained is proportional to the duration of the explanation to the speaker. So if you want to maximize the number of feedbacks you will need:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To talk to the speaker about the reasons you want to collect feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That the speaker includes a lapse of time (2-3 minutes) at the end of the session dedicated to the taking of feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That the speaker explains in turn why it is important for him and for the organizers to capture the feelings of the audience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The speakers should not feel hijacked by this evaluation, it is important that they understand that this information is useful for him to appreciate the value of his service from the audience’s point of view. The comments left are generally ways of improvement that will enable him to do better during his next presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Real time tracking&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is the best moment!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our platform offers “real” real time, that is to say that you will be able to observe live responses coming and summary tables of results filling themselves. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that as simply as opening a link from your smartphone, tablet, computer or even from a TV screen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-6-d-day--1&quot;&gt;Step 6: D day + 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Survey links&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
To collect even more feedback, you can also e-mail the participants afterwards by sending them the links to the different polls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This possibility is offered for the 15 days following the event. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sharing results&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
When people are polled about an event it is advisable to send them the results, in order to complete the loop!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We make available a sharing page with a summary of all polls of the day, publicly accessible via a secure URL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We invite the organizers to share this link whatever the means: mail, slack, or even social networks to reach to those who could not come?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Antoine Durand</name></author><category term="Events" /><summary type="html">You are an organizer of Conferences, REX, TEDx or other events of this type? You probably know better than us that getting feedback is a real puzzle that can be very time consuming and very expensive.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Agile en Seine 2018</title><link href="https://blog.roti.express//en/aes2018" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Agile en Seine 2018" /><published>2018-09-25T18:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-09-25T18:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://blog.roti.express//en/aes2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.roti.express//en/aes2018">&lt;p&gt;Agile En Seine 2018 was Tuesday, September 25th! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 550 participants and 28 talks on the topic of Agile in business, making it one of the major conferences of the French Agile ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;feedbacks--in-real-time-please&quot;&gt;Feedbacks ! (in real time please)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aes_results1_EN.png&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot; /&gt;
More than 430 feedbacks were received, thanks to our Roti.express platform, which measured the satisfaction rate of the sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were here all day long, and observed in real time the feedbacks on the arriving on the platform. At the exit of the rooms the speakers came to us to get a preview of their “scores”!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average score was 4.12/5, with an outstanding score of 4.91/5 for the inspiring talk of Virginie Guyot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These feedbacks were shared with the speakers and participants in a mindset of continuous improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://roti.express/feedback/aes2018&quot;&gt; Watch the full results Agile en Seine 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note : these results are in French, use the google translator if you want them in English !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-did-it-work-pretty-well&quot;&gt;Why did it work pretty well?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking feedback is always a tricky moment and can be really time-consuming, both for capture and analysis if it is poorly done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We announced that this will take place at the Keynote session and we quickly explained the rules of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To answer: no app to download, no tedious registration (login/password). I flash, I answer, and that’s it!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We did not force anyone to answer! And we were clear: “it’s not your data that interests us but your feedback on the event”.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We explained that the final results would be shared with everyone. Besides, we were already ready before the end of the event!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Taking feeback with the ROTI method (in Agile mode) was very suitable for this event!
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aes_feedback0.jpg&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;capturing-feedback-during-an-event&quot;&gt;Capturing feedback during an event?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We asked the speakers to put a giant QR-Code on the last slide of their Powerpoint presentation
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aes_feedback1.jpg&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for those who did not have time to flash the code we made posters in A3 format for each of the sessions, we put them on the doors of each conference room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We plastered a “QR-Code Wall” in the corridor that connects the different rooms!
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aes_wall.png&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;want-to-work-with-us-for-your-events&quot;&gt;Want to work with us for your events?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you organize conferences? REX? TEDx? We can help you collect feedback from participants&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact us directly by e-mail at : &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:survey@roti.express&quot;&gt;survey@roti.express&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(to be continued !)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Antoine Durand</name></author><category term="Events" /><summary type="html">Agile En Seine 2018 was Tuesday, September 25th! 550 participants and 28 talks on the topic of Agile in business, making it one of the major conferences of the French Agile ecosystem.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Infographics, Visuals &amp;amp; Goodies</title><link href="https://blog.roti.express//en/infographies-en" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Infographics, Visuals &amp; Goodies" /><published>2018-09-14T18:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-09-14T18:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://blog.roti.express//en/infographies-en</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.roti.express//en/infographies-en">&lt;p&gt;In order to make us known and to communicate with the general public, we asked Matthieu our graphic designer to design some visuals!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary-of-our-activity-in-1-image&quot;&gt;Summary of our activity in 1 image&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted a nice picture that summarizes our activity in 6 points in the manner of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mind_map&quot;&gt; mind-map &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exercise is much more difficult than it seems, because contrary to what we could think the less words you have the harder to get to the point.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Infographie_v2_eng.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot; /&gt;
That’s the result! Ideal to send on social networks or to print on a flyer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;more-specific-visuals&quot;&gt;More specific visuals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also wanted visuals with strong messages to market our solution on specific themes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took the option to use an “old fashioned” visual  with nice typos so that there is a real consistency in the messages.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/marketing.png&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot; /&gt;
These visuals will be used for social networks and for the advertising campaigns that we plan to launch in September 2018. Perhaps you have already seen them on some websites?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We love the result! so much so that we also made business cards to distribute in the trade shows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-famous-kakemono&quot;&gt;The famous “Kakemono”&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mandatory accessory of any good startuper, Kakemono literally “hanging object” means in Japan a painting or calligraphy roll intended to be hung on a mast. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In practice, it is rather the vertical computer graphics that one puts on one’s stand when one participates in an event or a show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/kakemono.png&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-goodies&quot;&gt;Other Goodies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because people are “fans” of our logo we have made various goodies out of it! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;stickers to place on your computer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;magnets that go on fridges or on the white boards in meeting rooms &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pins to hang on your jacket&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mugs to drink coffee&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soft fluffy toys in the shape of a roast!
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/goodies.png&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot; /&gt;
(to be continued!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Antoine Durand</name></author><category term="Marketing" /><summary type="html">In order to make us known and to communicate with the general public, we asked Matthieu our graphic designer to design some visuals!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The HappyTech community</title><link href="https://blog.roti.express//en/Happytech-en" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The HappyTech community" /><published>2018-09-09T18:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-09-09T18:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://blog.roti.express//en/Happytech-en</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.roti.express//en/Happytech-en">&lt;p&gt;Since its creation in 2017 we’ve been members of theHappyTech community, let’s go back this story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-happytech&quot;&gt;What is HappyTech?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of well-being at work is becoming increasingly important in companies and is a factor of productivity and performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;HappyTech: “Technology at the service of well-being at work”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the basic idea that drove the HappyTech communal to form, bringing together start-ups, business leaders and investors who work on a daily basis “to make the company a place where everyone can flourish and grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today HappyTech is: 34 member startups, more than 300 press articles, and for the staff :33 volunteers and 1 permanent worker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://france.happytech.life/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/happytech3.png&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea has made its way and several branches of HappyTech have opened in Europe, North America and even Australia! The new entities are federated under the International Committee of Happy Tech&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-we-doing-there&quot;&gt;What are we doing there?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Roti.express we are convinced that well-being at work is not just about putting a table football in the cafeteria!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a matter of fact, opening this bottom-top communication channel (from the bottom of the pyramid upwards in the hierarchy) has extremely beneficial effects, speech is free, axis of improvement emerge, and as it is, it is often from below that good ideas come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Listening actively to one’s employees is to take a first step towards their well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Improving meetings, workshops or any other group activities means increasing productivity, which is not decorrelated from well-being because it gives meaning to the events in which one invests time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I feel good when I come out of an effective meeting, I come home at night with a sense of satisfaction”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond providing a simple feedback platform we want to believe that we help change mentalities in business.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/plant.png&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;and-concretely-what-is-happening-at-happytech&quot;&gt;And concretely what is happening at HappyTech?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is above all an ecosystem: the members talk to each others regularly during the monthly event “Monthly Happy” to discuss our respective progress, and listen each-others pitching and to give advice, exchange business cards and sometimes customer leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allows startups to gain visibility, as an example , by participating in webinars or #MondayMotivation videos relayed on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/happytech/&quot;&gt;social networks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HappyTech also regularly organizes events in major companies to which member startups are invited, this is the opportunity to pitch in a small committee before a company that has shortlisted the startups it wants to meet.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/happytech4.png&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The communal is also present at important events such as VivaTech, LePoint conference or the Trophies of Well-being, in short we see them everywhere!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On its website Happytech also offers a &lt;a href=&quot;https://france.happytech.life/membres/&quot;&gt;catalog&lt;/a&gt; where the solutions of the members are presented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(to be continued!)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Antoine Durand</name></author><category term="Partners &amp; Friends" /><summary type="html">Since its creation in 2017 we’ve been members of theHappyTech community, let’s go back this story.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to fail your survey in 5 steps</title><link href="https://blog.roti.express//en/fail_survey-en" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to fail your survey in 5 steps" /><published>2018-09-04T18:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-09-04T18:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://blog.roti.express//en/fail_survey-en</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.roti.express//en/fail_survey-en">&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-begin-by-lying-to-the-respondents&quot;&gt;1. Begin by lying to the respondents&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So start with a sentence like “This survey will not take you more than 3 minutes” while you know it won’t, but as you want to have a maximum of answers you think it’s a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Consequence: You have a very good chance to fool people and they’llbelieve you … this time anyway!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-ask-a-lot-of-questions&quot;&gt;2. Ask a lot of questions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want to gather as much information as possible, and you think that this survey is an opportunity to put a maximum of questions to collect as much data as possible!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Consequence: at question 2 (text field, mandatory, min 50 words) you have already lost 80% of your audience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-offer-a-horrible-ux-user-experience&quot;&gt;3. Offer a horrible UX (User Experience) &lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A survey is something disposable, no one remembers it, so why bother doing something enjoyable to use?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Consequence: in addition to being endless, the interface is unpleasant or even bugged and the questions are inaccurate .. Congratulations! you lose more than 50% of your audience again&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-do-not-share-the-results&quot;&gt;4. Do not share the results&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results belong to you, and you intend to make the numbers say what you want in order to receive a premium and to please your manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Consequence: zero transparency, the survivors of your audience have just spent 25 minutes answering a questionnaire of which they will never see the result and on top of that the results are tampered .. There for sure, you have reached the summits!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-institute-the-bashing-culture&quot;&gt;5. Institute the bashing culture &lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because a survey is an opportunity to let off steam and empty one’s bag, do not close your questions and if possible make them mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Consequence: your survey’s a means of blowing off steam, there are no interesting information to draw, no hints at improvement, only the dissatisfaction of those you force to respond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/quoi_en.png&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-simple-and-damn-effective&quot;&gt;It’s simple, and damn effective!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The ROTI survey is composed of  &lt;strong&gt;2 questions&lt;/strong&gt;, always the same! and oriented only on &lt;strong&gt;1 évènement&lt;/strong&gt; at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The responding time is estimated at only  &lt;strong&gt;30 secondes&lt;/strong&gt; seulement (no more).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We offer a &lt;strong&gt;great UX&lt;/strong&gt; that works on computer, tablet, mobile without installing an app or even creating login / password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default the &lt;strong&gt;sharing of answers&lt;/strong&gt; is activated, and we propose to generate a sharing link to diffuse more widely in full &lt;strong&gt;transparency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We convey a culture of &lt;strong&gt;constructive feedback&lt;/strong&gt; that is the essence of our product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://roti.express&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/regles_en.png&quot; alt=&quot;Regles ROTI&quot; width=&quot;85%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(to be continued !)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Antoine Durand</name></author><category term="Epic Fail" /><summary type="html">1. Begin by lying to the respondents</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Feedback</title><link href="https://blog.roti.express//en/feedback-en" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Feedback" /><published>2018-08-05T18:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-08-05T18:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://blog.roti.express//en/feedback-en</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.roti.express//en/feedback-en">&lt;h3 id=&quot;fidbak&quot;&gt;\fid.bak\&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s go back for a moment to the concept of feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Feedback is something that happens in people’s minds after watching something (a meeting, a movie, a presentation, etc.) and very often, and unfortunately, it is not expressed in words&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;self-evaluation&quot;&gt;Self evaluation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During a performance, it is very difficult to self-evaluate, unless you record yourself .. and yet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is nevertheless a very precious element, moreover it is a natural thing to ask the question to others around you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For example after making a presentation the first thing I invariably do when I leave the room is to ask Guillaume: So how was I? did you like it? what did you think?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To ask for feedback is to benefit from other people’s points of view, and what interests us there is constructive criticism because it enables us to progress, to improve and to grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every human being is different and will have their own perception and feedback, if we strive to harvest a maximum of them we will obtain an objective opinion.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/team-feecback.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;sharing-ones-feedback-a-story-of-benevolence&quot;&gt;Sharing one’s feedback, a story of benevolence?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feedback is something I can choose to give or keep for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; I notice that my competitor who is about to present his product after me has a beautiful piece of lettuce stuck between his teeth: I choose not to give him my feedback!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michel, the building safety officer, has just given me a hour and half lecture on fire safety and the operation of foam fire extinguishers: I choose to give him my feedback! Look Michel it was very good but my feeling is that it was too long, you lost everyone in the first half hour, wouldn’t 45 minutes be sufficient enough? a practical exercise? a video maybe?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mindset&quot;&gt;Mindset&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also a matter of mindset behind all this: am I ready to hear feedback from a third party? Am I ready to hear a criticism that will allow me to improve?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is that most people want to improve and for them this reflex is natural.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are however exceptions ; people a little infatuated with themselves? tyrannical managers? who could tell me “I know what I’m doing and I have no advice to receive from you!” and it’s a shame because I wanted to tell you that you had a piece of salad between your teeth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In her book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.fr/Mindset-How-Fulfil-Your-Potential/dp/1780332009&quot;&gt;Mindset&lt;/a&gt;, which I recommend, Carol Dweck explains in detail the difference between a &lt;em&gt;fixed mindset&lt;/em&gt; and a &lt;em&gt;growth mindset&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;scrum-retrospective&quot;&gt;SCRUM retrospective&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a closer look at what SCRUM offers and in particular the Retrospective ritual, what is the purpose of a retrospective? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The retrospective is a ritual (a meeting) at the end of each sprint (iteration) during which the Scrum team accounts for its experience on the past sprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is therefore a moment of sharing in which each member of the team is asked to give their feedback in an open and transparent way! What are the successes? What are the failures? What could be done better in the next sprint?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;By doing a retrospective we provoke a feedback&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal for the team is to improve their organization in order to be more efficient, the retrospective is a key element of the principle of continuous improvement and enables the team to become self-learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(to be continued !)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Antoine Durand</name></author><category term="5 minutes on" /><summary type="html">\fid.bak\</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A ROTI in digital version</title><link href="https://blog.roti.express//en/digital-roti-en" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A ROTI in digital version" /><published>2018-08-04T18:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-08-04T18:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://blog.roti.express//en/digital-roti-en</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.roti.express//en/digital-roti-en">&lt;h2 id=&quot;digitalising-the-practice&quot;&gt;Digitalising the practice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;September 2017, we embark on the coding of our application, the objective is announced: we will make ROTI in digital version! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We start by asking ourselves about the specifications: what is a ROTI ritual?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;anatomy-of-the-roti-ritual-&quot;&gt;Anatomy of the ROTI ritual? ?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R.O.T.I. for “Return on Time Invested” is an agile, quick and easy method to evaluate time spent in meetings, workshops or conferences and collect / give feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The announced goal is to make these events more productive and satisfying for each participant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the intervention, each participant gives a mark on a scale from 1 to 5 by a show of hands.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/hands_en.png&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, in 30 seconds, they explain their rating to the host with a useful and benevolent comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/comments_en.png&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lets-digitalize&quot;&gt;Let’s digitalize&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the survey by a show of hands! In order to allow the participants to evaluate the time they have just spent in a meeting, we will propose them to give a number of stars:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/scoring_en.png&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;85%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for the under 30 seconds comment? It’s quite simple too, we start on a text field that is voluntarily limited to 1000 characters because we do not want the participants to tell us a long story, just to give us hints at improvement to do better next time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/commentaire1_en.png&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;85%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lets-add-value&quot;&gt;Let’s add value&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ROTI ritual is supposed to last 5 minutes, but in reality it is difficult for the host to take the evaluations and write down the comments, but for us it’s a piece of cake!
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/results_en.png&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;85%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then we can also group all this on a beautiful page that summarizes the comments!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/commentaires2_en.png&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;85%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;one-idea-leading-to-another&quot;&gt;One idea leading to another…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have reached our goal of a digitized ritual, we do as much or even more than what was expected&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also realize that when we collect data, it opens the way for us to explore its analytical possibilities. Track the surveys of the different teams, measure progress over time, offer a company level vision! Everything is now possible!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try it on our website &lt;a href=&quot;https://roti.express&quot;&gt;Roti.express&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(to be continued !)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Antoine Durand</name></author><category term="Our journey" /><summary type="html">Digitalising the practice</summary></entry></feed>