<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://blog.roti.express//en/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://blog.roti.express//en/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2018-10-31T12:44:05+01:00</updated><id>https://blog.roti.express//en/</id><title type="html">Roti.express Blog</title><subtitle>Le Blog Agile de Roti.express</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Guide: getting massive feedback for events</title><link href="https://blog.roti.express//en/events-en" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guide:  getting massive feedback for events" /><published>2018-10-16T18:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-10-16T18:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://blog.roti.express//en/events-en</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.roti.express//en/events-en">&lt;p&gt;You are an organizer of Conferences, REX, TEDx or other events of this type? You probably know better than us that getting feedback is a real puzzle that can be very time consuming and very expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;automating-the-taking-of-feedback&quot;&gt;Automating the taking of Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://roti.express&quot;&gt;Roti.express&lt;/a&gt; platform  allows to make massive feedback in a simple, fun, and really effective way! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With us, the steps for capturing feedback, recording answers and providing results are fully automated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And icing on the cake ; everything happens in real time! You’ll be able to observe the arrival of the results and the analytics filling as your event unfolds. All you need is a smartphone, a tablet or a computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of what we did for &lt;a href=&quot;https://roti.express/feedback/aes2018&quot;&gt;Agile en Seine 2018&lt;/a&gt; (500 participants)
&lt;a href=&quot;https://roti.express/feedback/aes2018&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aes_background1.png&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;60%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
That’s rather impressive, isn’t it? Let’sexplain how it works ;follow the guide!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-1-ask-for-a-quotation&quot;&gt;Step 1: Ask for a quotation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An event of this magnitude is more complicated than a meeting and we’ll need to have some information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of participants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date and Duration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of sessions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you need us on the site?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Why are we asking all this?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
In order to ensure the quality of the incoming feedback and to receive important loads on the platform we provision machines (servers, load balancer etc ..) to absorb the peaks of simultaneous connections.
&lt;br /&gt;All this is planned up ahead, and requires a little work on our part!
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/event_offering_en.png&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;30%&quot; /&gt;
The quote request is done through e-mail, you can contact us directly at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:survey@roti.express&quot;&gt;survey@roti.express&lt;/a&gt;. We’ll get back to you as soon as possible!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-2-your-workspace&quot;&gt;Step 2: Your workspace&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we have reached an agrement we will create your workspace, then you will receive a link to join the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is from this space that you will be able to administer the event: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choose a name and customize your logo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create and set polls&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Retrieve QR-Codes and share links&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;View all detailed results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your workspace is open for a period of 30 days: the opening takes place 15 days before the event to prepare it and the closing is 15 days later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data you have collected does not disappear from the platform, and the sharing pages remain accessible (unless you specify otherwise). When we say “closing” the platform we mean that the participants can not vote after a period of 15 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-3-creating-polls&quot;&gt;Step 3: Creating polls&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are then getting into the heart of the subject, we must create for each intervention the associated survey by indicating:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The name of the session&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The name of the speaker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date, time and duration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;as well as some parameters (visibility, anonymous answers, etc.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be clear if your event consists of 30 sessions, it will be necessary to create 30 polls! This is a bit of work, we recommend doing it a few days in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-4-qr-codes-and-sharing-links&quot;&gt;Step 4: QR-Codes and sharing links&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the polls have been created you will get two things&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The share link (URL to reply to the survey)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A QR-Code, which also points to this sharing link &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These elements will allow you to collect feedback automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;QR codes&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The best way to get feedback is “while they’re still hot” just at the end of the intervention. You will need to ask your speakers to be kind enough to integrate a QR-Code on the last slide of their PowerPoint presentation.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/hand.png&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Affiches&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
From your workspace you have the possibility to create posters that contain the name of the session and the QR-Code, we recommend placing these posters at the exits of the conference rooms and printing them in A3 format.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aes_wall.png&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-5-the-d-day&quot;&gt;Step 5: The D day&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Explain carefully the approach to the speakers&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
From what we have been able to observe the number of answers obtained is proportional to the duration of the explanation to the speaker. So if you want to maximize the number of feedbacks you will need:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To talk to the speaker about the reasons you want to collect feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That the speaker includes a lapse of time (2-3 minutes) at the end of the session dedicated to the taking of feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That the speaker explains in turn why it is important for him and for the organizers to capture the feelings of the audience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The speakers should not feel hijacked by this evaluation, it is important that they understand that this information is useful for him to appreciate the value of his service from the audience’s point of view. The comments left are generally ways of improvement that will enable him to do better during his next presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Real time tracking&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is the best moment!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our platform offers “real” real time, that is to say that you will be able to observe live responses coming and summary tables of results filling themselves. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that as simply as opening a link from your smartphone, tablet, computer or even from a TV screen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-6-d-day--1&quot;&gt;Step 6: D day + 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Survey links&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
To collect even more feedback, you can also e-mail the participants afterwards by sending them the links to the different polls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This possibility is offered for the 15 days following the event. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sharing results&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
When people are polled about an event it is advisable to send them the results, in order to complete the loop!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We make available a sharing page with a summary of all polls of the day, publicly accessible via a secure URL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We invite the organizers to share this link whatever the means: mail, slack, or even social networks to reach to those who could not come?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Antoine Durand</name></author><category term="Events" /><summary type="html">You are an organizer of Conferences, REX, TEDx or other events of this type? You probably know better than us that getting feedback is a real puzzle that can be very time consuming and very expensive.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Agile en Seine 2018</title><link href="https://blog.roti.express//en/aes2018" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Agile en Seine 2018" /><published>2018-09-25T18:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-09-25T18:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://blog.roti.express//en/aes2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.roti.express//en/aes2018">&lt;p&gt;Agile En Seine 2018 was Tuesday, September 25th! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 550 participants and 28 talks on the topic of Agile in business, making it one of the major conferences of the French Agile ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;feedbacks--in-real-time-please&quot;&gt;Feedbacks ! (in real time please)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aes_results1_EN.png&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot; /&gt;
More than 430 feedbacks were received, thanks to our Roti.express platform, which measured the satisfaction rate of the sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were here all day long, and observed in real time the feedbacks on the arriving on the platform. At the exit of the rooms the speakers came to us to get a preview of their “scores”!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average score was 4.12/5, with an outstanding score of 4.91/5 for the inspiring talk of Virginie Guyot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These feedbacks were shared with the speakers and participants in a mindset of continuous improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://roti.express/feedback/aes2018&quot;&gt; Watch the full results Agile en Seine 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note : these results are in French, use the google translator if you want them in English !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-did-it-work-pretty-well&quot;&gt;Why did it work pretty well?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking feedback is always a tricky moment and can be really time-consuming, both for capture and analysis if it is poorly done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We announced that this will take place at the Keynote session and we quickly explained the rules of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To answer: no app to download, no tedious registration (login/password). I flash, I answer, and that’s it!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We did not force anyone to answer! And we were clear: “it’s not your data that interests us but your feedback on the event”.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We explained that the final results would be shared with everyone. Besides, we were already ready before the end of the event!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Taking feeback with the ROTI method (in Agile mode) was very suitable for this event!
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aes_feedback0.jpg&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;capturing-feedback-during-an-event&quot;&gt;Capturing feedback during an event?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We asked the speakers to put a giant QR-Code on the last slide of their Powerpoint presentation
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aes_feedback1.jpg&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for those who did not have time to flash the code we made posters in A3 format for each of the sessions, we put them on the doors of each conference room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We plastered a “QR-Code Wall” in the corridor that connects the different rooms!
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aes_wall.png&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;want-to-work-with-us-for-your-events&quot;&gt;Want to work with us for your events?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you organize conferences? REX? TEDx? We can help you collect feedback from participants&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact us directly by e-mail at : &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:survey@roti.express&quot;&gt;survey@roti.express&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(to be continued !)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Antoine Durand</name></author><category term="Events" /><summary type="html">Agile En Seine 2018 was Tuesday, September 25th! 550 participants and 28 talks on the topic of Agile in business, making it one of the major conferences of the French Agile ecosystem.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Infographics, Visuals &amp;amp; Goodies</title><link href="https://blog.roti.express//en/infographies-en" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Infographics, Visuals &amp; Goodies" /><published>2018-09-14T18:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-09-14T18:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://blog.roti.express//en/infographies-en</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.roti.express//en/infographies-en">&lt;p&gt;In order to make us known and to communicate with the general public, we asked Matthieu our graphic designer to design some visuals!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary-of-our-activity-in-1-image&quot;&gt;Summary of our activity in 1 image&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted a nice picture that summarizes our activity in 6 points in the manner of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mind_map&quot;&gt; mind-map &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exercise is much more difficult than it seems, because contrary to what we could think the less words you have the harder to get to the point.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Infographie_v2_eng.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot; /&gt;
That’s the result! Ideal to send on social networks or to print on a flyer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;more-specific-visuals&quot;&gt;More specific visuals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also wanted visuals with strong messages to market our solution on specific themes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took the option to use an “old fashioned” visual  with nice typos so that there is a real consistency in the messages.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/marketing.png&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot; /&gt;
These visuals will be used for social networks and for the advertising campaigns that we plan to launch in September 2018. Perhaps you have already seen them on some websites?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We love the result! so much so that we also made business cards to distribute in the trade shows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-famous-kakemono&quot;&gt;The famous “Kakemono”&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mandatory accessory of any good startuper, Kakemono literally “hanging object” means in Japan a painting or calligraphy roll intended to be hung on a mast. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In practice, it is rather the vertical computer graphics that one puts on one’s stand when one participates in an event or a show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/kakemono.png&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-goodies&quot;&gt;Other Goodies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because people are “fans” of our logo we have made various goodies out of it! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;stickers to place on your computer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;magnets that go on fridges or on the white boards in meeting rooms &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pins to hang on your jacket&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mugs to drink coffee&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soft fluffy toys in the shape of a roast!
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/goodies.png&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot; /&gt;
(to be continued!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Antoine Durand</name></author><category term="Marketing" /><summary type="html">In order to make us known and to communicate with the general public, we asked Matthieu our graphic designer to design some visuals!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The HappyTech community</title><link href="https://blog.roti.express//en/Happytech-en" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The HappyTech community" /><published>2018-09-09T18:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-09-09T18:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://blog.roti.express//en/Happytech-en</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.roti.express//en/Happytech-en">&lt;p&gt;Since its creation in 2017 we’ve been members of theHappyTech community, let’s go back this story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-happytech&quot;&gt;What is HappyTech?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of well-being at work is becoming increasingly important in companies and is a factor of productivity and performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;HappyTech: “Technology at the service of well-being at work”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the basic idea that drove the HappyTech communal to form, bringing together start-ups, business leaders and investors who work on a daily basis “to make the company a place where everyone can flourish and grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today HappyTech is: 34 member startups, more than 300 press articles, and for the staff :33 volunteers and 1 permanent worker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://france.happytech.life/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/happytech3.png&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea has made its way and several branches of HappyTech have opened in Europe, North America and even Australia! The new entities are federated under the International Committee of Happy Tech&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-we-doing-there&quot;&gt;What are we doing there?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Roti.express we are convinced that well-being at work is not just about putting a table football in the cafeteria!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a matter of fact, opening this bottom-top communication channel (from the bottom of the pyramid upwards in the hierarchy) has extremely beneficial effects, speech is free, axis of improvement emerge, and as it is, it is often from below that good ideas come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Listening actively to one’s employees is to take a first step towards their well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Improving meetings, workshops or any other group activities means increasing productivity, which is not decorrelated from well-being because it gives meaning to the events in which one invests time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I feel good when I come out of an effective meeting, I come home at night with a sense of satisfaction”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond providing a simple feedback platform we want to believe that we help change mentalities in business.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/plant.png&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;and-concretely-what-is-happening-at-happytech&quot;&gt;And concretely what is happening at HappyTech?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is above all an ecosystem: the members talk to each others regularly during the monthly event “Monthly Happy” to discuss our respective progress, and listen each-others pitching and to give advice, exchange business cards and sometimes customer leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allows startups to gain visibility, as an example , by participating in webinars or #MondayMotivation videos relayed on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/happytech/&quot;&gt;social networks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HappyTech also regularly organizes events in major companies to which member startups are invited, this is the opportunity to pitch in a small committee before a company that has shortlisted the startups it wants to meet.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/happytech4.png&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The communal is also present at important events such as VivaTech, LePoint conference or the Trophies of Well-being, in short we see them everywhere!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On its website Happytech also offers a &lt;a href=&quot;https://france.happytech.life/membres/&quot;&gt;catalog&lt;/a&gt; where the solutions of the members are presented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(to be continued!)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Antoine Durand</name></author><category term="Partners &amp; Friends" /><summary type="html">Since its creation in 2017 we’ve been members of theHappyTech community, let’s go back this story.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The worst meeting in my entire life</title><link href="https://blog.roti.express//en/origins-en" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The worst meeting in my entire life" /><published>2018-08-03T18:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-08-03T18:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://blog.roti.express//en/origins-en</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.roti.express//en/origins-en">&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-day-it-all-started-&quot;&gt;The day it all started …&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summer 2017, I am consultant in a mission for a client who is starting a digital transformation, big project over 2 years, critical and strategic for the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s 14:00 and I attend my first “weekly meeting”, I’m not the meeting facilitator but a simple participants, let’s start !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there I experienced the worst meeting of my life, everything went wrong:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;14 people were invited: physical &amp;amp; online with skype&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;some participants were (very) late&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;there was no agenda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;some topics without any connection to the meeting were discussed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;no output / todo-list&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I thought I had reached the bottom when I noticed that one of the participants allowed himself to answer his phone during the meeting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was watching the disaster, when suddenly in my head the little Agile coach said :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“at the end of the meeting we absolutely have to get feedbacks from the participants and make sure that this nightmare does not repeat next week”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this moment I am thinking of ROTI (Return On Time Invested), this easy and quick agile ritual that enables you to quickly evaluate the satisfaction with the meeting and get some means of improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;frustration&quot;&gt;Frustration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started late, and of course we finished late, the clock is running, the room is reserved, the participants have other meetings that are already starting, the Skype participants are disconnecting … no more time to do the Roti, I feel like a fool, alone with my idea of getting feedback, I feel hopeless&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went home terribly frustrated and on the way back (in the subway) I decided:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“It does not matter, I could not do it live but I’ll do it offline, I have the email addresses of everyone and I intend to ask for their feedback through e-mail”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent a good part of the evening looking for a tool that would simply ask those two questions to the participants:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On a scale of 1 to 5 how would you rate the time spent on this meeting?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What could be improved for next time?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/ok_google.png&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;85%&quot; /&gt;
After reviewing what Google offers and various survey tools I ended up realizing that there was no tool that would answer simply to my need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;creation&quot;&gt;Creation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, next steps came quickly! It is 9pm I contacted Guillaume (the other co-founder) by phone, I explained my problems of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideas are spinning in our heads, it’s no longer just a feedback tool that we are thinking about, but an online platform that allows companies to do ROTI surveys instantly, track their progress over time, identify quickly a meeting that goes wrong : continuous improvement applied to meetings!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our minds are set, the following days I wake up at 5am to draw the screens, Guillaume writes the first lines of codes, we decide on a name “roti.express” and choose a nice logo !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prototype, MVP, cloud architecture, field tests, scalability, acceleration at Station F! … But all this is another story, see you in the next article!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(to be continued !)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Antoine Durand</name></author><category term="Our journey" /><summary type="html">The day it all started …</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Roti.express Blog opening</title><link href="https://blog.roti.express//en/welcome" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Roti.express Blog opening" /><published>2018-07-27T18:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-07-27T18:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://blog.roti.express//en/welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.roti.express//en/welcome">&lt;p&gt;Hello and welcome to our blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s nice to see you here! In September 2017, a year ago, we designed the first screens and wrote the first lines of code of our Roti.express application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Since last year many things have happened and we decided to launch this blog to tell you about our adventures! Come back soon, you will not be disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime we invite you to watch &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K_E4HGfBCpQ&quot;&gt;a short 59 seconds video&lt;/a&gt; that explains what Roti.express is about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/K_E4HGfBCpQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you already know what it is, &lt;a href=&quot;https://roti.express/start&quot;&gt;just start your first survey&lt;/a&gt; for your events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Guillaume Darbonne</name></author><category term="Hello World !" /><summary type="html">Hello and welcome to our blog.</summary></entry></feed>