<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://blog.roti.express//en/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://blog.roti.express//en/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2018-10-20T15:54:25+02:00</updated><id>https://blog.roti.express//en/</id><title type="html">Roti.express Blog</title><subtitle>Le Blog Agile de Roti.express</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Agile en Seine 2018</title><link href="https://blog.roti.express//en/aes2018" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Agile en Seine 2018" /><published>2018-09-25T18:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-09-25T18:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://blog.roti.express//en/aes2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.roti.express//en/aes2018">&lt;p&gt;Agile En Seine 2018 was Tuesday, September 25th! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 550 participants and 28 talks on the topic of Agile in business, making it one of the major conferences of the French Agile ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;feedbacks--in-real-time-please&quot;&gt;Feedbacks ! (in real time please)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aes_results1_EN.png&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot; /&gt;
More than 430 feedbacks were received, thanks to our Roti.express platform, which measured the satisfaction rate of the sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were here all day long, and observed in real time the feedbacks arrive on the platform. At the exit of the rooms the speakers came to find us to know their “score” in preview!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average score is 4.12/5, with an outstanding score of 4.91 for the inspiring talk of Virginie Guyot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These feedbacks are shared with the speakers and participants in a mindset of continuous improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://roti.express/feedback/aes2018&quot;&gt; Watch the full results Agile en Seine 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note : these results are in French, use the google translator if you want them in English !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-did-it-work-pretty-well&quot;&gt;Why did it work pretty well?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking feedback is always a tricky moment and can be really time-consuming, both for capture and analysis if it is poorly done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We announced that this will take place at the Keynote session and we quickly explained the rules of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To answer: no app to download, no tedious registration (login/password). I flash, I answer, and that’s it!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We did not force anyone to answer! And we were clear: “it’s not your data that interests us but your feedback on the event”.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We explained that the final results would be shared with everyone. Besides, we were already ready before the end of the event!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Taking feeback with the ROTI method (in Agile mode) was very suitable for this event!
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aes_feedback0.jpg&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;capturing-feedback-during-an-event&quot;&gt;Capturing feedback during an event?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We asked the speakers to put a giant QR-Code on the last slide of their Powerpoint presentation
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aes_feedback1.jpg&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for those who did not have time to flash the code we made posters in A3 format for each of the sessions, we put them on the doors of each conference room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have installed a “QR-Code Wall” in the corridor that connects the different rooms!
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aes_wall.png&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;want-to-work-with-us-for-your-events&quot;&gt;Want to work with us for your events?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you organize conferences? REX? TEDx? We can help you collect feedback from participants&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact us directly by e-mail at : &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:survey@roti.express&quot;&gt;survey@roti.express&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(to be continued !)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Antoine Durand</name></author><category term="Events" /><summary type="html">Agile En Seine 2018 was Tuesday, September 25th! 550 participants and 28 talks on the topic of Agile in business, making it one of the major conferences of the French Agile ecosystem.</summary></entry></feed>